import{j as t}from"./index-IeqH0dFg.js";import{_ as e}from"./english-abbreviations-58DH1woZ.js";const n={sections:[{header:{text:"Put the verbs in the correct form",translation:"Поставьте глагол в правильную форму"},global:{fill:{normalize:{ignorePunctmarks:!0}}},exercises:[{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"I"},{preFill:"to like",rightAnswerRegex:["like","i"]},{text:"apples."}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"Ann"},{preFill:"to play",rightAnswerRegex:["plays","i"]},{text:"computer games every weekend."}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"We"},{preFill:"to go",rightAnswerRegex:["go","i"]},{text:"to work by train."}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"You"},{preFill:"not to work",rightAnswerRegex:[`do${e} work`,"i"]},{text:"very hard."}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"My friend and I"},{preFill:"to spend",rightAnswerRegex:["spend","i"]},{text:"time together in the evenings."}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"They"},{preFill:"to visit",rightAnswerRegex:["visit","i"]},{text:"their relatives once a week."}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"I"},{preFill:"not to swim",rightAnswerRegex:[`do${e} swim`,"i"]},{text:"in the see on summer."}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"Food"},{preFill:"to become",rightAnswerRegex:["becomes","i"]},{text:"cold in the fridge."}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"My cat"},{preFill:"not to enjoy",rightAnswerRegex:[`does${e} enjoy`,"i"]},{text:"fish."}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"Her parents"},{preFill:"not to take",rightAnswerRegex:[`do${e} take`,"i"]},{text:"her to school every day."}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"We"},{preFill:"not to invite",rightAnswerRegex:[`do${e} invite`,"i"]},{text:"our friends at the weekend."}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"You"},{preFill:"to know",rightAnswerRegex:["know","i"]},{text:"Math."}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"Sarah and Andrew"},{preFill:"not to go",rightAnswerRegex:[`do${e} go`,"i"]},{text:"to dancing classes on Sundays."}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"We"},{preFill:"to have",rightAnswerRegex:["have","i"]},{text:"our English lessons twice a week."}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"He"},{preFill:"not to have",rightAnswerRegex:[`has${e}`,"i"]},{text:"blue eyes."}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"I"},{preFill:"to have",rightAnswerRegex:["have","i"]},{text:"dark hair."}]]}]},{header:{text:t.jsxs(t.Fragment,{children:["Choose the right form of verb ",t.jsx("b",{children:"to be"})]})},exercises:[{type:"test",question:"Molly and Johnny ____ my dogs.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"are",2:"am",3:"is"}},{type:"test",question:"My father ____ a bad toothache.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"has got",2:"have got",3:"am"}},{type:"test",question:"We ____ a computer, but we are going to buy it.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"don't have",2:"aren't have",3:"hasn't"}},{type:"test",question:"What time ____ he usually come home after job?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"does",2:"has",3:"do"}},{type:"test",question:"____ you from Russia?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"are",2:"am",3:"is"}},{type:"test",question:"____ what I want?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Does Barbara know",2:"Barbara knows",3:"Do Barbara knows"}},{type:"test",question:"I ____ not your friend.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"am",2:"is",3:"are"}},{type:"test",question:"What's the matter? You ____ very angry.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"look",2:"looks",3:"looking"}},{type:"test",question:"I ____ like dancing.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"don't",2:"doesn't",3:"aren't"}},{type:"test",question:"Laura's mother ____ from Australia.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"is",2:"am",3:"are"}},{type:"test",question:"____ you ____ any time to help me? – Sorry, I ____.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Do you have ... don't",2:"Have you got ... am not",3:"Do you have ... have got"}},{type:"test",question:"____ they ____ Spanish well?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Do ... speak",2:"Does ... speak",3:"Do ... speaks"}},{type:"test",question:"____ your mother often ____ to the theatre?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Does ... go",2:"Is ... go",3:"Do ... go"}},{type:"test",question:"They ____ German.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"are",2:"am",3:"is"}},{type:"test",question:"Patrick ____ English but he ____ German",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"speaks ... doesn't speak",2:"speak ... not speak",3:"speaks ... doesn't speaks"}},{type:"test",question:"____ you ____ where your mother ____ ?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Do ... know ... is",2:"Do ... know ... was",3:"Are ... know ... is"}},{type:"test",question:"The boy ____ to school every day.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"goes",2:"will goes",3:"go"}},{type:"test",question:"Autumn is cold here. It ____ very seldom. But sometimes it ____.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"snows ... rains",2:"rain ... snows",3:"snow ... rain"}},{type:"test",question:"Daddy and I often ____ Mummy about the house.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"help",2:"helps",3:"helpes"}},{type:"test",question:"I ____ that man because I ____ German.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"don't understand ... don't know",2:"not understand ... don't know",3:"don't understand ... not know"}}]},{header:{text:"Choose the correct option"},exercises:[{type:"test",question:"____ Tommy like video games?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Does",2:"Is",3:"Has"}},{type:"test",question:"I ___ a baker.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"am",2:"is",3:"are"}},{type:"test",question:"Maria is very good at tennis. She ______ every game.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"wins",2:"gets",3:"won"}},{type:"test",question:"We _____ like Tim and Tim ____ like us",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"don't ... doesn't",2:"are not ... isn't",3:"do ... not"}},{type:"test",question:"Madrid and Barcelona ___ cities in Spain.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"are",2:"am",3:"is"}},{type:"test",question:"____ any brothers or sisters?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Does grandpa have",2:"Have grandpa got",3:"Does grandpa has"}},{type:"test",question:"Lucy and I ______ for a company, which ______ toys.",rightAnswerIds:["2"],answers:{1:"works ... produces",2:"work ... produces",3:"work ... produce"}},{type:"test",question:"They ___ Italian.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"are",2:"am",3:"is"}},{type:"test",question:"____ Jackie Sith ____ English?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Does ... speak",2:"Is ... speak",3:"Do ... speak"}},{type:"test",question:"His mother ______ him there in her car.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"takes",2:"take",3:"taken"}},{type:"test",question:"____ any milk in the fridge?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Does Perry have",2:"Do Perry has",3:"Have Perry got"}},{type:"test",question:"We ___ children.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"are",2:"am",3:"is"}},{type:"test",question:"I ____ that girl because I ____ Chinese.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"don't understand ... don't know",2:"not understand ... don't know",3:"don't understand ... not know"}},{type:"test",question:"I ____ this rule. Can you help me?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"don't understand",2:"doesn't understand",3:"understands"}},{type:"test",question:"My daughter Macy ____ lemons, but she likes oranges.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"doesn't like",2:"not likes",3:"doesn't likes"}},{type:"test",question:"____ your brother often _____ to the cinema?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Does ... go",2:"Is ... go",3:"Do ... go"}},{type:"test",question:"Donald ___ a doctor.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"is",2:"am",3:"are"}},{type:"test",question:"My brother and I often _____ Mummy about the house.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"help",2:"helps",3:"helpes"}},{type:"test",question:"Mark and his brother ____ wonderful voices.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"have got",2:"does",3:"has got"}},{type:"test",question:"______ you ______ where your sister ______ ?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Do ... know ... is",2:"Do ... know ... was",3:"Are ... know ... is"}}]}]};export{n as default};
